Woodrow Wilson Collection, 1837-1986 (bulk 1883-1924 ): Preliminary Finding Aid MC168
Public Policy Papers
- Series 2: Correspondence, 1810-1992; 17 Volumes; 34 boxes
  - Special Correspondence Collections, 1852 January 10-1932; 17 Volumes; 10 boxes
    - Woods, Lawrence, 1904-1925; 1 box
      - 3 TLsS, Wilson, Woodrow to Woods, Lawrence C, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 4 TLs (carbons), Woods, Lawrence C. to Wilson, Woodrow, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 3 TLsS, Bolling, John Randolph, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to McCormick, Cyrus H, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 1 printed card, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 1 clipping, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - [ 1 TLS, Bolling, John Randolph, to Wood, James C, 1921; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - 1 telegram, Wilson, Woodrow to Woods, Lawrence C, 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 2 TLsS, Bolling, John Randolph, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Bolling, John Randolph, 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 1 ALS, E. E. B. to Woods, Lawrence C. (and Mrs. Woods), 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 1 TLS, McCormick, Cyrus H. to Woods, Lawrence C, 1922; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 18)
      - 1 telegram, Wilson, Woodrow to Woods, Lawrence C, 1923; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - 2 TLsS, Bolling, John Randolph, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1923; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Bolling, John Randolph, 1923; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - 1 ALS, Wilson, Edith Bolling,to Woods, Lawrence C, 1923; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 19)
      - 4 TLsS, Bolling, John Randolph, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 telegram, Bolling, John Randolph, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 TL (Carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to J. R. B, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 2 ALsS, Wilson, Edith Bolling, to Woods, Lawrence C, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 TLS, Wilson, Edith Bolling to Woods, Lawrence C, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Gerould, James Thayer, 1924; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - 1 ALAS, Wilson, Edith Bolling, to Woods, Lawrence C., Woods, Lawrence C, 1925; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - 1 TL (carbon), Woods, Lawrence C. to Gerould, James Thayer, 1925; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 21)
      - Unidentified fragment, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 22)
      - 2 certificates, A founder of the Woodrow Wilson Award, Life member of the American National Red Cross, 1917 September 1; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 23)
      - oversize document, gift of Hyatt, Thaddeus P., Appointment of Ezell, Lula, as postmaster of Thimpson, Texas, DS, 1916 January 7; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 23)
      - oversize document, gift of Hyatt, Thaddeus P., Proclamation, "Red Cross Week,", 1918 May 20; 1918 May 7; 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Woods, Lawrence C., Xeroxes and Photostats, 1904-1925; 1 box
      - 1904-1911, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - 1912-1914, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - 1915-1917, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - 1918-1925, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - 1904-1911, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - 1912-1914, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - 1915-1917, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - 1918-1925, 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Photostats of correspondence, 1909-1925; 1 folder (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Yates, Frederic, 1902-1926; 1 box
      - 2 ALsS, 7 TLsS, Yates, Frederick, By Wilson, Woodrow, 1906-1913; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - 5 TLsaS by Wilson, Woodrow, 1914; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - TMs (carbon) by Remon, Auguste, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - 6 TLsS by Wilson, Woodrow, 1916-1919; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - 1 TLS by Wilson, Woodrow to Mrs. Yates, 1923; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - 1 ALS by Wilson, Edith Bolling to Mrs. Yates, 1923; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - 1 ALS by Wilson, Ellen Axson to Mrs. Yates, 1908; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - 1 ALS (fragment) including photographs of Wilson, Eleanor R. and Wilson, Margaret Woodrow, 1907; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - 2 postcards picturing Prospect House, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - 6 ALsS by Wilson, Ellen Axson to Yates, Frederick, 1907-1912; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - 3 ALsS by Wilson, Ellen Axson to Yates, Emily Chapman Martin (Mrs. Frederick Yates), 1909-1913; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - 1 ACS, 1914; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - 1 ALS by Wilson, Margaret W. to Yates, Mary, 1914; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - 1 AL (fragment) by Yates, Frederick (?), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - 3 ALsS by Wilson, Jesse to Yates, Mary, 1912; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - 1 ALS by Wilson, Jesse to Yates, Mary, 1912; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - 2 printed invitations, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - 1 clipping, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - ALS by Wilson, Margaret Woodrow to Yates, Mary, 1908; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - 1 printed invitation (regarding Wilson, Eleanor R. and McAdoo, William G.), Yates, Frederic, 1914; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - 1 printed invitation (regarding Galt, Edith Bolling and Wilson, Woodrow) and 1 rotogravure copy, 1915; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - 1 ALS, 1918; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - 1 TLS, Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1918; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - 3 ALsS, Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1915-1919; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - 15 ALsS (including several fragments), Yates, Frederic to Mrs. Yates, 1910-1913; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 14)
      - 3 ALsS by Baker, Ray Stannard to Mrs. Yates, 1925; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - 1 AL (fragment), 1925; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - 7 TLsS, 1925-1926; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - 1 clipping, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 15)
      - 2 ALsS, Axson, Margaret Randolph to Mrs. Frederic Yates, 1907-1921; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Printed matter, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 16)
      - Diary of Yates, Mary, 1908; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 17)
      - Photographs Wilson, Ellen Axson (2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Bohemian Club dinner, 1912; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Chalk portrait (copy) Wilson, Woodrow, 1902; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Picture post cards of Wilson, Woodrow (2), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Printed invitation (fragment), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Newspaper clipping, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 18)
      - Memorabilia, postcards with views of Princeton, 1910; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 19)
      - Memorabilia, election, 1912; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 20)
      - Memorabilia, Washington, D.C. (at the time of Wilson, Woodrow inauguration), 1913; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 21)
      - Memorabilia regarding Wilson, Woodrow inauguration, 1913; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 22)
      - Printed matter by Wilson, Woodrow, Yates, Frederic, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 23)
      - Printed matter clippings about Wilson, Woodrow, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Copies of Letters in Other Collections, 1882-1946; 1 box
    - 1 TL (copy), Alexander, Mr, 1902; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat), Apple, Henry H, 1910; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Baker to Hamlin, C. S., Baker, Newton D, 1924; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Baker, Newton D, 1916; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - 1 ALsS (Photostats), 1882-1884; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 1 ACS (Photostat), Bridges, Robert, undated; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat), 2 copies, Bridges, Robert, 1887; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - 3 TLsS (Photostat), Clark, Melton and Mrs. Clark (Lottie), 1913-1915; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Colby, Bainbridge, 1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - 4 TLs (copies) by Wilson, Woodrow to Creigh, 1910-1911; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - 4 TLS (copies) by Creigh to Wilson, Woodrow, 1910-1911; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - 1 TLS by Creigh to Dodds, Harold W, 1943; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Dodds, Harold W. to Creigh, 1943; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - 2 TLsS (Photostats), 1907; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - 1 TDS (Photostat), Lionberge, Davis J, 1917; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) with ANS to "Rolo" Dripps, 1897; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - 1 ADS (Photostat), Dripps, J.F., 1897; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat), 1915; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Dunlap, John R. (Photostat), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - 3 TLsS (Xeroxes), 1910-1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - 1 printed letter signed (Photostat), Eisenhart, Luther Pfahler, 1912; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Ewing, Nathaniel, 1909; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - 10 TLsS (photostat), Frazer, A. M, 1903-1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat), George, A. J, 1897; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - 2 TLsS (Xeroxes), Gerould, G. H, 1905; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - 3 TLsS (xeroxes), Griffis, William Elliot, 1905-1923; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - (1 letter signed by Wilson, Woodrow's secretary), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - 1 ALS (xerox) by Wilson, Jesse W. to Griffis, 1912; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - 1 printed letter (xerox), 1913; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - Copies of 44 letters – see enclosed list, Harvey, George, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - 7 AlsS xeroxes), 1888-1901; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - 9 TLsS, Hazen, A.W., 1910-1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - 1 AL (copy), 1909; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - 1 typescript, Henry, Thomas W., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 21)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat), Hewison, James King, 1919; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 22)
    - 24 letters (Photostat) between Wilson, Woodrow and Hibben, as well as Wilson, Ellen A. and Mrs. Hibben, Hibben, John Grier and Mrs. Hibben, 1899-1919; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 23)
    - 5 TLsS (Photostats) by Wilson, Woodrow to Hooker, Hooker, Richard, 1916-1918; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - 1 night letter (Photostat) by Hooker to Wilson, 1918; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat) by Wilson to Baruch, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Baruch to Hooker, 1940; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 24)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Hull, Charles A, 1911; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 25)
    - 1 TLS (facsimile) by Wilson, Woodrow to Hurley, Hurley, Edward N, 1918; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - 1 TLS (facsimile) by Wilson to Harlan, John M, 1910; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - 1 TLS by Hurley to Kemmerer, Edwin Walter, 1928; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 26)
    - 1 TLS by Brand, Katharine E. to Eisenhart, Luther P, 1946; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Smith, Albridge C., Jr., to Wilson, Woodrow, 1907; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Murphy, Franklin to Wilson, Woodrow, 1907; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - 1 TL (copy) by Morgan, J. J. to "dear Sir" (originals in the possession of the Library of Congress), the Library of Congress, 1907; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 27)
    - 1 ALS (xerox), MacMurray, John Van Antwerp, 1907; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 28)
    - 1 TL (copy), McPherson, Simon John, 1903; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 29)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Meredith, William M, 1916; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 30)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat), Milliken, H. O, 1905; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 31)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat), 1909; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - 1 TN (Photostat), Rankin, Walter M, 1945; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 32)
    - 2 copies TLS (Photostats), 1913; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - 2 copies document (Photostats), 1912; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - 1 telegram by Tumulty, Joseph P. to Reichner, Reichner, L. Irving, 1913; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 33)
    - 22 ALsS (Photostats), Reid, Harry Fielding, 1897-1923; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - 16 TlsS (Photostat), 1912-1921; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat) by Wilson, Woodrow to Reid, Harry Fielding), 1898; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 34)
    - 39 transcriptions of Photostats in previous Folder, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - 1 ANS by Reid, Doris Fielding to Mahan, Mrs. Burnett, 1946; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 35)
    - 25 TLsS (Photostat), 1912-1918; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - 2 TLsS (Photostats) by Tumulty, Joseph P, 1915; 1917; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - 2 TLs (copies) (Photostat), Saulsbury, Willard, 1912; 1916; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 36)
    - ALS (Photostat), Seidensticker, Mr, 1911; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 37)
    - 1 AL (Photostat), 1891; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - 1 ALS by Smith to the Princeton University Library, Smith, Edwin O, 1945; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 38)
    - 18 TLsS (Photostat) to various correspondents, see enclosed list (originals in the possession of the University of Tampa), University of Tampa, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 39)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Wilson, Edith Bolling to Seely, L., (originals in the possession of the University of Tampa: see preceding Folder), 1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Wilson, Edith Bolling to Seely, L., (originals in the possession of the University of Tampa: see preceding Folder), 1922; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Tumulty, Joseph P. to Holt, Hamilton, (originals in the possession of the University of Tampa: see preceding Folder), 1920; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by House, Edward M. to Ferguson, Charles, (originals in the possession of the University of Tampa: see preceding Folder), 1914; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 40)
    - 6 TLS (copies) (Photostats), correspondence among Wilson, Woodrow, McAdoo, William G., Storey, Moorfield and Villard, Villard, Oswald Garrison, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 41)
    - 1 telegram (Photostat) to Woodrow, B. (Mrs.), Wilson, Joseph R, 1912; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 42)
    - 6 TLsS (Photostats), Wilson, William L, 1910-1914; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 43)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Wilson, Wilson, Woodrow, 1898; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 44)
    - 1 TLS (xerox), Wilson, Wilson, Woodrow, 1898; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 45)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat), Woodrow, "Felie", 1915; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - 6 TLsS (Photostat), Woodrow, James (Mrs.), 1915-1920; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Sayre, Francis B. to "Aunt Felie", 1915; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - 1 printed announcement (Photostat), 1915; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 46)
    - 2 TLsS (Photostat), Woodrow, James, 1901; 1903; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 47)
    - 8 TLsS (Photostats), 1911-1921; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 48)
    - 1 TLS (Photostat) by Bolling, John Randolph to Woodrow, Marion W, 1921; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 48)
    - 1 ALS (Photostat) by Reid, Walter (Mrs.), to Woodrow, Marion M., Woodrow, Marion W, 1921; 1 folder (Box 39, Folder 48)
- Series 3: Documents, 1891-1983; 1 box
  The Documents Series includes originals and photostats of many important documents written, signed, or received by Woodrow Wilson, including applications, appointments, constitutions, resolutions, and property and deed documents. Of note are the marriage license of Woodrow Wilson and Edith Bolling Galt, as well as "Resolutions Regarding the Graduate School of Princeton University, 1908."
  The Documents Series is arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Applications for absentee ballot, Wilson, Edith Bolling for the 1920 November 2 election, 1920 October 19, 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Appointment of Johnstone, E. R., to be a delegate to the 38th annual session of the National Conference of Charities and Correction DS, 1911 May 2; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Articles of Agreement between Wilson, Woodrow and Garrett, Robert regarding Princeton property- AD (carbon), 2 pp., 1902 September 4; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Authorization of payment to Wilson, Norman R. of $24.08 TDS, 1905 July 29; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Check of First National Bank for $50.00 endorsed by Wilson to Pershing, John J. and endorsed by Pershing DS (Photostat), 1917 October 25; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Constitution of the Liberal Debating Club, Princeton ADS (Photostat), 13 pp., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Data for general catalogue of Princeton University, 1906; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Deeds and searches relating to Princeton property, 1891-1906; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Library of Princeton University call slip, 1897 August 30; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Marriage license issued to Wilson, Woodrow and Galt, Edith Bolling (Photostat), 1915 December 16; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of the faculty of Princeton University on the resignation of Wilson, Woodrow from the presidency TD, 3 pp., 1919 November 21; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Proclamation-Red Cross Week for second war fund campaign (see oversize document for original), 1918 May 18-27; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Promissory note to Wilson, Woodrow by Ford, Henry J., endorsed by both Wilson and Ford DS, 1913 February 5; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Receipt for $10.00, caution money, Johns Hopkins University, 1983; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Release of author's rights to publisher (The Perry Mason Company) regarding "The Personal Factor in Education" DS, 1906 March 10; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Resolutions regarding the Graduate School of Princeton University TD (carbon), 1908; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Statement of appreciation to the 15,000 Four Minute Men of the United States TDS, 1917 November 9; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Trustees Minutes (in part), including the report of the election of Wilson, Woodrow as president of Princeton University TD (Photostat), 2 pp., 1902 June 9; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 18)
  - Vital statistics for class of '79 Register, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Documents, 1916 January 7-1918 May 20; 1 box
    (See Oversized, Box 108)
    - Appointment of Lula Ezell as postmaster of Timpson, Texas; DS, 1916 January 7; 1 box (Box 40)
    - Proclamation, "Red Cross Week," 1918 May 20 DS, gift: Thadeus P. Hyatt, 1918 May 7, 1 box (Box 40)
- Series 4: Images, Portraits, Photographs, Caricatures, 1875-1946; 3 boxes
  The Images, Portraits, Photographs, Caricatures Series contains etchings, prints, photographs, lithographs, and paintings of Woodrow Wilson, his family and associates, his residences, and related topics visually documenting his life. The series includes the G. E. Thompson Collection, as well as many miscellaneous and oversized images.
  The Images, Portraits, Photographs, Caricatures Series maintains the organization given to it as new items were aquired; basic catagories include G. E. Thompson Collection, Wilson Family Photos, Miscellaneous, Photos, Prints of Wilson and Wilson Related, and Oversized.
  - Thompson, G. E., Collection, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Missing Numbers 12, 19, 31, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Wilson Portrait, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - 2 signed photographs 9" x 12", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Wilson Portrait (woven lacquered picture), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Wilson family photographs, dates not examined; 1 box
    - Wilson Portraits, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Wilson Family Photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Wilson and Edith Bolling Wilson, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous, 1875-1946; 1 box
    - Princeton Undergraduate Years, 1875-1879; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Princeton, Faculty Member and President, 1890-1913; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Governor of N. J, 1910-1913; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - President of the United States, 1913-1921; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 4)
    - Europe, 1915-1919; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 5)
    - Final years, 1921-1924; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Associates, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Residences, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous photographs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - S. S. "president Wilson", 1946; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Etchings by Hall, Charles B. and Smillie, G.F.C., dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Photographs, Prints of Wilson and Wilson Related, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
  - Oversized Photographs, 1879-1913 March 4; 1 box
    (See Oversized, Box 107, 109-112, 117)
    - Photographs Oversize: Photograph of Inaugural of President Wilson at Washington, D.C., 1913 March 4; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Photographs: Oversize; 1 caricature, 1 collage ("Wilson – That's All" – from liquor advertisement), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Photographs: Oversize; Princeton Faculty with President Woodrow Wilson includes Alan Marquand, 1903 (2 images), 1 box (Box 43)
    - Photograph of Wilson and unidentified group, [ML 1993-2], dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Class of 1879 (14 images), 1 box (Box 43)
    - New York Times, New York World, Portraits of Wilson, 1 partial panorama of Paris Peace Conference (3 images), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - "A Tribute to Woodrow Wilson Democracy Embracing the World" (carbon gold painting), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Woodrow Wilson House, Woodrow Wilson Foundation, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Oval Portrait of Wilson, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Oil Painting, Estelle Levy, "Garden in Old Lyme, Connecticut" (a favorite walk of Wilson), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Woodrow Wilson for Governor, Campaign Poster/Photograph, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Etchings/Lithograph of Wilson (3 items), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous Portraits, dates not examined; 1 box (Box 43)
    - Photograph of Inaugural of President Wilson at Washington, D. C, 1913 March 4; 1 box (Box 43)
      (Oversized 11, UnBoxed positioned on top of 3/16/15/1)
    - Photographs of Wilson Residences, undated; 1 box (Box 43)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      ML.2019.012
- Series 5: Memorabilia, 1879-1935; 2 boxes
  The Memorabilia Series includes booklets, pamphlets, sheet music and other items from different eras of Wilson's life, documenting his undergraduate years at Princeton, his presidency of Princeton, his governorship and his presidency of the United States.